Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lumbar
General Insurance Company Limited Q2 and
H1 FY2025 earnings conference call
from the senior management team. We have
with us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr. Gopal
Balachandran CFO
Mr. Girishesh Nayak, Chief Technology
and Health Underwriting and Claims, Mr.
Sep Gada, Chief Corporate Solutions
Group and Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief Retail
and Government Business.
Please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involves risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in the listenonly mode. There
will be an opportunity for you to ask
questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during this
conference, please signal the operator
by pressing star and then zero on your
touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir. Thank you.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earning conference
call of ICLA General Insurance Company
Limited for quarter 2 NH1 financial year
2025.
Let me give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the ensuing months.
Post this, our CFO Mr. Gopal Balachan
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and a half
year ended September 30th, 2024.
During the quarter 1 2025,
India's real GDP grew by 6.7% primary
driven by private consumption. Moving
into the Q2 or financial year 2025, the
government expenditures started
witnessing an uptick. GST collections
continue to remain steady and Q for Q2
and the direct tax collections are
growing at a decent pace. This may
provide much neededed support to retail
spending in the upcoming festive season.
Further, a normal monsoon may help drive
rural demand in coming month.
Nevertheless, the current situation in
West Asia region and a substantial
increase in crude prices remains a major
risk for the overall economic growth.
Speaking of general insurance
performance, the industry delivered a
GDPI growth of 7% for H1 of financial
year 2025 over H1 of financial year 2024
impacted by quarter 2 financial year
2025 growth of 2%. However, excluding
crop and mass cell segments, the
industry registered growth at 10.9% for
H1 of 2025 and 6.9% for quarter 2
financial year 2025.
Now talking about the auto industry
growth for the quarter was muted as
reported by CM. Private car with higher
base degree at 1.8%.
Two pillars grew at 12.6% and CV degree
at 3.2%.
This this entails approximately 2.1
million private cars, 10.2 million two
wheelers and8 million CVs being sold in
H1 of 2025. Further, the retail numbers
as reported by far has also seen
degrowth for private car at 5.1%, two
wheeler growth at 4.7%
and CV growth remain muted at 1.1% for
quarter 2 financial year 2025.
The health segment during the quarter
continued to deliver double-digit growth
largely driven by retail business
registering growth of 17.7%.
The growth in the group business was
moderated due to phasing pressure and
the health business was impacted due to
relatively muted disbbursement by
financial institutions.
The commercial line segment during the
quarter was a mixed bag with industry
growth at 2%. While fire segment degree
at 10.7% on account of pricing pressure.
However, government spend on
infrastructure development and
acceleration in private sector
investment has spurred positive growth
especially in segments such as
engineering, liability and marine.
The regulatory environment continues to
focus on policyholders interest while
fostering innovation, competition and
sustainable growth for the industry
thereby reinforcing the authorities
vision of insurance for all by 2047.
Overall for the medium to long term we
remain positive that the general
insurance industry will continue to grow
given the favorable regulatory changes,
low penetration and rising disposable
income.
Now speaking of the underwriting
performance of the industry, the
combined ratio for the industry remain
at 113.9% for quarter 1 financial year
2025 as against 113.5% for quarter 1
financial year 2024.
For the motor business, the industry's
combined ratio woren to 125.6% 6% in
quarter 1 financial year 2025
from 121% in quarter 1 2024 which can be
largely attributed to the increase in
loss ratios.
Now let me update you on performance of
key business segments for us. The
company's GDPI for quarter 2 financial
year 2025 grew by 10.4% as compared to
the industry growth of 2%.
Excluding crop and mass sales the
company grew by 9.4% 4% as compared to
the industry growth of 6.9%.
In the commercial line segment we grew
at 1.22% as against industry growth of
2%.
We continue to maintain leadership
position in engineering liability and
marine cargo segment. However, in the
fire segment we remain vigilant in terms
of risk selection while maintaining a
market share.
In motor segment during the quarter we
registered a growth of 16.1% as against
the industry growth of 6.2%.
The overall growth in motor segment
during the quarter was aided by growth
in whole business.
We continue to maintain a market share
leadership with robust capabilities
across distribution and writing claims
servicing and actial practices. During
the quarter we sustained a balanced
portfolio with a mix of private car, two
wheeler and CV at 54.4%. 4% 24.6% and
21% respectively.
Our preferred partner network enabled us
to service 72.8% of our nonEM claims in
quarter 2 of 2025, up from 63.4% in
quarter 2 of financial year 2024.
The health segment grew at 12.3% in
quarter 2 financial year 2025. Led by
retail health, we registered a growth of
41.4% 4% in quarter 2 2025 as against
industry growth of 17.7% in the retail
health segment. Our growth in quarter 2
was supported by our recently launched
product elevate. Our market share for
retail health segment has now reached
3.5% in quarter 2 of financial year
2025.
In the group health employer employee
segment we look we took a cautious
approach due to increased competitive
intensity. Conse consequently we grew by
1% in quarter 2 financial year 2025 as
compared to growth of 34.6% in quarter 1
of financial year 2025.
During the quarter our bank of business
debut by 2.6% 6% due to lower credit
disbursement growth in our key
relationship partners
within this ICA group dis distribution
grew by 19.6% 6% for quarter two of
financial year 2025 due to a continued
strategic focus on branch banking
business. We continue to strengthen our
digital business. During the quarter,
our customerf facing digital business
grew by 14.7%
constituting 6.3% of our overall GDPI.
Our investments in new customer
acquisition strategies through website
led to a growth in fresh business of
motor and health segment by 45.9% in
quarter 2 financial year 2025.
Our one-stop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs. The take care app
has surpassed 11.6 million user
downloads till date registering a
premium of 55 55 56.8 million for the
quarter.
As discussed in a previous call, we
continue to harness synergies through
one is one team. Under this one one of
our initiative one is one call center.
We have consolidated multiple call
centers into three specialized teams.
Fresh acquisition, renewals and
servicing to drive improvement in
operational efficiencies and the overall
customer experience. Additionally, our
investment in CRM technology and AI
tools have further increased
productivity by high teams and improved
customer service particularly in retail
health and motor segments. In
conclusion, we continue to strengthen
our multi-product multi-distribution
strategy led by a focus on product
innovation, data analytics and digital
enhancements. These initiatives coupled
with the spirit of one team position as
well to capitalize on future
opportunities and drive profitable
growth. I will now request Gopal to take
you through the financial numbers for
the recently concluded quarter and half
year. Thanks Ajiv and uh good evening to
each one of you. I will now give you a
brief overview of the financial
performance of the recently concluded
quarter and half year. We have uploaded
the results results presentation on our
website. You can access it as we walk
you through the performance numbers.
Gross direct premium income of the
company was at rupees 144.09 billion in
H1 FI25 as against rupees 124.72 billion
in H1 FI24 a growth of 15.5%
against the industry growth of 7%.
Excluding crop and mass health, GDPI
growth of the company was at 15%. Which
was higher than the industry growth of
10.9% in H1 FI25.
GDPI was at rupees 67.21 billion in Q2
FI25 as against rupees 60.86 billion in
Q2 FI24, a growth of 10.4%.
This again was higher than the industry
growth of 2%. Excluding crop and mass
sales, GDP growth of the company was at
9.4% 4% which was higher than the
industry growth of 6.9% in quarter 2
FI25. Our GDPI growth during the quarter
was mainly driven by preferred lines of
businesses. On the retail side of the
business, GDPI of the motor segment was
at rupees 24.82 billion in Q2 FI25 as
against rupees 21.38 billion in Q2 FI24
registering a growth of 16.1%.
The advanced premium number was rupes
35.13 billion as at September 30, 2024
as against rupes 34.56 billion as at
June 30, 2024.
GDP of the health segment was at rupes
15.29 billion in Q2 FI25 as against
rupes 13.62 billion in Q2 FI24 again
registering a growth of 12.3%. Our
agents which includes the point of sale
distribution count was 1 lak 33,683
as on September 30, 2024 up from 1 lakh
31,021 as at June 30, 2024. The overall
GDP of our commercial line segment grew
by 1.2% at rupes 14.93 billion in Q2
FI25 as against rupees 14.76 billion in
Q2 FI24.
During the quarter the industry
witnessed multiple catastrophic events
namely floods in Andra, Telangana, North
India, Gujarat etc etc impacting our
combined issues which was 103.2% for H1
FI25 as against 103.8% 8% for H1 FI24
excluding this impact of CAT losses
which was rupees 94 billion in H1 FI25
and rupees.83 billion in H1 FI24. The
combined ratios were 102.2%
and 102.7%
respectively. Combined ratio was 104.5%
in Q2 FI25 as against 103.9 in Q2 FI24.
Again excluding the impact of CAT losses
primarily we had the CAT losses in Q2
this year which was again rupees.94
billion and rupes48 billion in Q2 FI24.
The combined ratio was 102.6% and 102.8%
respectively. Our investment assets
during the quarter rose to rupes 515.57
billion as at September 30 2024 up from
rupes 510.04 billion as at June 30 2024.
Our investment leverage net of borings
was 3.91 times as at September 30 2024
as against 4.14 times as at June 30,
2024.
Investment income was at rupes 22.52
billion in H1 FI25 as against rupes 18
billion in H1 FI24.
On a quarterly basis, investment income
was at rupes 11.24 24 billion in Q2 FI25
as against rupes 9.56 billion in Q2
FI24.
Our capital gains net of impairment on
investment assets stood at rupees 5.21
billion in H1 FI25 as against rupes 2.82
billion in H1 FI24. Capital gains net of
impairment on investment assets for the
quarter to FI25 stood at rupees 2.37
billion as compared to rupees 1.65
billion in Q2 FI24. Our profit before
tax grew by 31.9% at rupees 16.93
billion in H1 FI25 as against rups 12.84
billion in H1 FI24 whereas CBT grew by
20.3% at rupees 9.19 billion in Q2 FI25
as against rupees 7.64 billion in Q2
FI24. Consequently profit after tax grew
by 31.7% at rupees 12.74 billion in H1
FI25
as against rupees 9.68 68 billion in
huge FI24.
Profit after tax again grew by 20.2% for
this quarter to FI25 at 6.94 billion
rupees up from rupees 5.77 billion in Q2
FI24.
Return on average equity was 20.3% in H1
FI25 as against 18% in H1 FI24. The
return on average equity for Q2 FI25 was
21.8%
as against 21.1% in Q2 FI24. Solveny
ratio was healthy at 2.65 times as at
September 30 2024 as against 2.56 times
as at June 30, 2024 continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times. The board of
directors of the company has declared an
interim dividend of rupees 5.5 per share
for H1 FI25 as against rupees 5 per
share which was for H1 FI24.
As I conclude, I would like to reaffirm
that we continue to stay focused on
driving sustainable value creation and
profitable growth while protecting the
interest of policy holders at all times.
I would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any questions that
you may have. Thank you.
Thank you very much. We will now begin
the question and answer session. Anyone
who wishes to ask a question may press
star and one on their touchstone
telephone. If you wish to withdraw
yourself from the question queue, you
may press star and two. Participants are
requested to please use handsets while
asking a question. Ladies and gentlemen,
we will wait for a moment while the
question queue assembles.
The first question is from the line of
Shrea Shivani from CLSA. Please go
ahead. Uh thank you for the opportunity.
Uh I have two questions. Uh first is on
the net commission rate for the quarter.
It seems like it's slightly elevated
when I compare it to the second quarter
of last year. Could it be uh because of
uh higher sales in the retail health
segment? Are we have we changed uh our
commission structure in that product or
is it just because the product mix has
shifted more towards that mix uh that
segment? Uh that's the first question.
And second uh sir uh majority of the
rise uh in the in the combined ratio in
this quarter has been because of the
catastrophic losses. uh so uh uh will we
still hold on to our guidance of being
able to touch 101.5 the as a closing
combined ratio in 4q25
uh given that majority from catastrophe
and in case we don't see any more
surging so uh just the guidance around
that thank you yeah I think Gopar will
answer the first one and I'll talk about
the guidance yeah so sh I think uh
you're absolutely right I think uh so
far as the net commission ratio numbers
are concerned it's obviously a function
of uh the mix of business that you
underwrite and uh as you would have seen
I think our approach to writing risk as
as what we put out also as a part of the
open opening transcript was to drive
profitable growth and therefore in that
context when you look at the mix of
business largely what we have been able
to drive is profitable businesses in
motor and uh the retail health segment
in specific and relative to that I think
our growth in let's say the group
health/ commercial lines
have been relatively muted and that's
clearly a factor that has contributed to
let's say the change in the net
commission ratio and given the fact that
we have also been a bit cautious on the
commercial line there is also some bit
of impact in so far as uh reinsurance
commissions are concerned so because the
ratio is on a net commission basis so
therefore it is a factor of both change
in business mix as well as let's say our
approach to being a bit cautious on the
commercial line commercial line side
which is what has contributed to the net
commission numbers. To your point on
have we changed anything in so far as u
commission structures are concerned. I
think the short answer is uh I think we
keep looking for market opportunities in
terms of how we want to write businesses
but at an aggregate level I think what
we stand committed is to kind of make
sure that from an expense of management
standpoint which includes both
commission plus operating expenses both
of that put together as a company we
stand committed to make sure that we are
well within the limit of uh 30% at an
aggregate level yeah so overall you're
right the cat event uh in the quarter
two has impacted the loss ratio by 7.9%
and thereabouts. Uh otherwise overall
the command is of the company if net of
cat event is looked at that's shown an
improvement. Uh uh in terms of the
guidance as things stand uh we have no
reason to change the guidance at this
point of time. Uh we we very keenly will
look at the industry numbers also as
they come out on the quarter 2 and the
H1 P&L. uh I spoke about uh in my own uh
script which I said uh that the quarter
one number for the industry has come out
uh relatively status quo while we used
to have a yi improvement uh uh last year
and that also has come on account of
elevated loss ratio and little bit of
impact on account of uh expenses
uh we stay committed we have no reason
to at this point of time deviate from it
uh we do look at the intensity and the
landscape that you seen the commentary
to overall as to what's happening on the
commercial line of business. Uh we grew
GHR business at almost 31% and
thereabouts. Uh we and the quarter two
again you look at the numbers we have
gone down and we clearly do understand
that uh uh these are all changes the
fire business has uh had gone through a
bit of a concern in terms of where the
discounting has increased again. uh
we've abstained from any uh wild
participation and still we've been able
to maintain a market share on uh on each
of these uh business lines. So yes we
stay committed to that but we continue
to watch the market scenario. I think to
just to only add to that sh I think what
we would say is uh in fact uh we will
start seeing this impact felt from an
overall market as well. Um and if you
would have seen in general given our
ability to risk select portfolios our
exposure from some of these CAT events
have been relatively lowered compared to
the natural market share that we have
had as a company and hence a large part
of this change consequent to the CAT
losses will also be reflected from a
market perspective at the time of the
reinsurance renewals that will start
happening from the next year. So in fact
the real impact is something that you
will start seeing from an industry
standpoint at the time of the
reinsurance renewals which will kick in
for next year.
Got it. Understood. So you're you're
saying your reinsure your catastrophe
reinsurance will be priced uh worse off
for us for the industry going ahead
right
these are events that are playing out
right. So honestly if you ask us could
we have anticipated let's say about four
events coming and hitting us at an
industry level in one quarter the short
answer is no. And therefore and with
let's say wavering weather patterns that
you're seeing uh across periods honestly
I think one will have to kind of wait
and see how this develops and then maybe
as things move forward we will be able
to start giving you better insight.
Yeah. Got it. Very useful. Thank you so
much and all the best. Thank you. Thank
you. Ladies and gentlemen, we request
you to please restrict your questions to
two questions per participant. You may
rejoin the queue for follow-up
questions.
We have the next question from the line
of Pra Jen from Motila Los. Please go
ahead.
Yeah. Hi, good evening everyone. Uh just
a question this question on uh the motor
segment. So in our last quarter you had
mentioned about uh the growth in uh new
versus old. Uh so it would be great if
you could share a similar trajectory for
H1 and just an extension to that whether
you know if the the growth in the in the
renewal or the older business or the new
vehicle has been stronger. what are the
drivers for the same that you have been
kind of been able to get more more
growth there and uh second question
would be on the motor outlook again uh
you mentioned in the opening remarks
that the growth has been slowing down in
terms of number of vehicles
uh and so do you see and whatever the
outlook that we are hearing is that it
outlook is also going to be muted in the
uh second half even for season the
demand outlook is not expected to Great.
So what kind of growth trajectory should
be anticipate for the motor segment
especially in the H2? Yeah, those would
be my question.
The first on the first one I think uh uh
if you recolct what we had said in
quarter one when the aggregate growth in
motor for us was about 26%. At that
point of time we had said the growth in
new was about 16 and the growth in
renewal was roughly about 33%. Um and
given what we had talked about as a part
of this opening transcript in terms of
as you rightly indicated new being
relatively muted uh pretty much on
similar lines I think if you ask us for
quarter 2 the growth in new has been
flattish uh and a large part of the
growth of that 16% that we spoke about
has been significantly aided by growth
in the renewal book or let's say the old
book which has grown at almost about
26%. Uh so that's a split this is
specifically in the context of quarter 2
uh viz what we had seen in uh Q1 to your
point on what's driving let's say some
of this uh growth I think u as a company
I think we have always been kind of
looking at uh which we have spoken about
even on earlier calls I think while we
stay invested in obviously leveraging
our relative strength on OEM/ dealership
partnerships but at the same time we
have also been significantly investing
on our agency/ Ash uh other
distributions as well and um in that
context our our strength on distribution
service use of technology all of that is
what is kind of significantly aiding the
growth in the renewal book plus equally
if you recolct what we also talked about
was also to kind of significantly move
into let's say a one call center
initiative under which we we had wanted
to kind of which is also what we put out
as a part of the opening transcript to
kind of also have a significant focus as
one of the streams in so far as
retentions are concerned and that is
also in uh in a big way is aiding the
growth in the uh old book. Yeah. So on
the second point on the motor outlook
you're right uh the uh the overall
numbers that have come out uh for the
industry has been muted and there's
nothing new that we are talking about
it. it's all over every possible you
know uh uh channel as to where the
industry is. Uh but I must also
highlight one fact that on private car
in particular which contribute more than
50% of our uh practice as far as motor
is concerned uh it's on a very high
base. We had a very secular run on
private car as an industry uh almost you
know when the covid was still there and
then it kind of continued for a while.
So on a very high base if it is flattish
also it does not overtly concerns us. Uh
yes and two wheeler has shown better
numbers but two wheeler also had
recovered only 80 85% of precovid levels
while private car has moved in the zone
of 130 to 140% of what it was precoid
peak. Uh commercial vehicle mixed bag
but uh which can be a proxy in many ways
to the uh industrial activity uh which
takes place. We do believe it can pick
up in quarter end of quarter three or
maybe in you know by quarter four. Uh so
overall yes we are expecting a single
digit growth uh in H2 but uh that itself
should suffice and this also is a
backdrop that uh as an industry we've
had not much of a TP hike uh for almost
uh you know last three years if I may
say. So it's it's a it's a combined
factor uh which stays but we stay
committed to harness what works for us.
So there is uh we we are excited with H2
also and the festive season has just got
started. Foods have been high. Uh the
sales numbers are still building up.
Probably we'll have a much better sense
how the festive season goes by uh by
November mid and thereabout once the
Diwali part is over.
Just a clarification on this. Uh you
mentioned the single digit growth that
you expect in X2 is for vehicle sales or
is it for the premium growth of the
motor segment for generation? No, I'm
I'm I'm talking about the premium the
vehicle sale is what I'm referring to.
Vehicle sale. Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. All right. Thank you.
Thank you. Thank you.
The next question is from the line of
Madukar Ladha from Noama Wealth
Management Limited. Please go ahead. Hi
uh good evening sir. Uh so so um first I
think in your opening remarks you
mentioned that on the motor segment
industry combined uh ratios have
worsened. Now um in this backdrop I
think H1 your performance has been very
good and um and you know do you think
that this will be sustainable?
um um given you know industry loss
ratios are worsened and so uh how how do
you think uh you know this can uh pan
out? Do you think uh
uh it it the competitive intensity is is
got higher or uh yeah so that's that's
question number one.
Hello and second
you want to put your second question if
you have yeah I should answer this.
No. And second s uh you know last year
uh we were sort of discussing that uh
IDI a lot of your competition is sort of
above the 30% uh um you know expense and
commission ratio. So and is not in
compliance of the um norms. So uh is IID
looking to do something about it? what
is the thought process of there because
um you know that may help in getting
industry combined ratios uh under check
and and we can benefit in that scenario.
Yeah. So so f I think uh so I'll uh
answer both of them. Uh on the core side
when you spoke about motor the core for
the industry has moved from 121 to
125.6.
So clearly it's worsened.
uh when you look at the loss ratio on
that uh the industry had in quarter 1
last year loss ratio of 84.5 it gone to
87.6
and there's an increase on the expense
side also which has taken it from 36.5
to 38%. Uh interesting place when you
split this in PSU and private sector
clearly PSUs has worsened from 134 to
uh driven by again significant increase
in loss ratio private from 107 to 115.
So that has been the kind of a movement
that you have seen in loss ratio for PSU
for private sector in particular. It
also in a way answers as to what Lombard
can look at. It has remained in the zone
of 74.2 to 75%. So it's and there's a
marginal increase in the private sector
as far as expense ratio is concerned
where it moved from 41.1% to 43.5.
uh so from the balance perspective and
where journey can be while I don't want
to stretch the line too far we stay
committed and we do back ourselves on
two count uh one is uh in terms of the
selection that we are able to do as an
entity and secondly the manner in which
we are able to service our customer
which is at speed and in a far more
efficient manner. So all of that in
combined uh we would love to you know
probably put this across that we stay
committed to where we are. Uh yes at an
industry level finally we are part of
our uh overall uh you know operations of
the business. Uh as things stand uh we
would love to see improvement at the
industry level also because if that
happens it can create further niche for
us and improve our combined ratio. So
that's my you know uh uh take and here
we stay committed to you know take care
of a motor practice. We would be agile
enough to make movement between private
carheer and commercial vehicle as it
warrants at that in a dynamic manner at
any point of time. Uh on the second
question in terms of the stuff that we
mentioned on expense of management yes
the data is out it's there with the
regulators. Uh we are in no position to
put a comment. We continue to pursue
with them as to what strictctures they
will do at some point of time. Uh there
are multiple nodes and there's lot of
proactive work being done by the
regulator multiple counts including the
master circular which has come uh for
each of the product categories. So we do
believe something is in the offic but uh
uh we are in no position to comment as
to when and how this would get
transpired.
Right. But you definitely expect some
action to bring the industry in line. I
from from our position we definitely
will expect but we are not the right uh
uh you know set of you know people to
comment as to how and when they will do
it that prerogative fairly and squarely
stays with them. But yes we do expect
that uh some uh action will be taken by
them at some point of time. So and and
one more question finally on the health
segment. Health segment loss ratios have
sort of worsened in the first half and
Q2 I I know seasonally is a little bit
of a weaker quarter in that respect but
is there any uh you know structural
problem in the industry you know
uh is pricing adequate what is your
sense? So uh we continue to monitor this
closely structural problem. My answer is
no. Are there challenges which comes on
account of some bit of seasonality which
leads to increase in frequency? Answer
is yes. There is an element of that
mazuka that does uh come in. And uh
nevertheless uh the way the process
works and the way the regulators create
the environment if there are challenges
each one of us is well within the rights
to you know seek a reprising of the
portfolio. Uh so in an agile mode all
this can be addressed over a period of
time.
Got it sir. Thank you and all the best.
Thank you mother. All the best. Thank
you. Thank you.
We have the next question from the line
of Sankit Goha from Vender Spark. Please
go ahead.
Uh yeah, thank you for the opportunity.
Um Gopal can you split the motor growth
uh uh for for the quarter and for the
half into new and the old and and in
this old can you give a bit of color
that this old is driven by the existing
customers that is they are renewing uh
what they bought last year with you or
is it the business which is coming from
other companies because because compared
to the industry we we seems to be
gaining significant share of market um
in this business. So, so if you can give
a color bit there and how sustainable it
is, it will be useful to to understand
the future outlook too. And and the
second question related to that is that
if you are doing more old in OD then
ideally the loss ratio should
deteriorate in OD but what but we are
seeing an improvement in 1 H or one
quarter compared to the last year. So,
so just wanted to understand what is
playing in our favor to to see that
better loss ratio in motor and and
lastly on on PP I believe you you guys
said last time that loss ratio of 65 to
70 is the number what you need to watch
out for and that's the guidance you have
given um and and and that was last year
and now now it is below 65 for first
half uh just just wondering given there
is no TP price hike whether whether you
believe this number is uh still
sustainable because I'm asking this
question from the perspective that in
last three years lost triangles that is
23 22 21 you did not choose to take any
reserve release uh uh from from from
motor TP so so so just just wondering
whether whether this number is
sustainable or not and lastly if you can
give a data point uh health loss ratio
broken down into retail and group that's
it all right perfect superb uh thanks
Thanks. Uh so one uh I think I'll take
it in the in the sequence which is the
I'll start with large and go to the
first. Uh so all the break up of the
health roio which is something that you
obviously ask us every quarter. Uh so
hence to that extent uh quarter two of
last year on the employer employee side
that number was 102%. Vizer with that
quarter two of this year that number is
about 98. uh on the retail indemnity
again quarter 2 numbers are roughly
about 66.6% and uh quarter two of this
year is about 70.3
uh but again as the point that we have
always maintained is uh I think if you
look at on the employer employee side
largely we have said I think the
portfolio should possibly end the year
in that range of over 94 95%. uh this is
I'm referring to the corporate health
and on the retail side I think broadly
we have talked about trying to run the
portfolio at a loss ratio around that
70% threshold so that's where we are
kind of largely working towards at least
in so far as the portfolio buildup is
concerned and to your third question on
the TP uh loss ratio range that we spoke
about I think when I talked about at an
aggregate motor segment level we had
said broadly the range that we are
comfortable operating at is between 65
to 67% % and within that we had said OD
possibly are looking at running between
60 to 65 and third party as you rightly
mentioned was between the range of 65 to
70. uh what we also keep saying is uh
honestly I think you should keep kind of
keep looking at numbers more on ideally
multiple annual cycles because these are
third party books which typically runs
over multiple uh long-term periods in
terms of development and to that extent
I think at this point of time I think we
kind of uh stay within that range of
what we spoke about which is motor at an
aggregate level of 65 to 67 and within
that third party we believe should
broadly kind of run at a range of about
65 5 to 70 and and and that that also
kind of resonates with one of the other
points that you rightly mentioned which
is what we are also seeing is obviously
no TP price increases and therefore to
that extent that's another factor that
we will be equally be mindful of in
terms of how we kind of select uh the
portfolios uh so that's in response to
question three to your point on question
two on the OD loss ratios I think I kind
of largely answered as a part of
question three which is I think the
range that you see even on a half yearly
basis or even within that uh if you look
at on quarter two broadly that loss of
shore range on own damage has been
running between uh in that range of
about 60 to 65 but uh having said that I
think uh one of the things that we have
been speaking about even in our earlier
earnings call is I think there is a lot
of thrust and focus on us to make sure
that we are able to significantly
leverage on the service parameters uh
particularly on trying to see how we can
manage the overall cost of claims in the
context of motors specifically. And if
you remember one of the initiatives that
we spoke about driving in that front was
to leverage on our PPN network. Uh and
there again if you would have seen uh
what we have tried to do is to the
proportion of claims that has got
settled through the PPN network the
numbers have kind of uh clearly seen an
uh increase. So all in all I think uh
pretty much comfortable with the range
at which we are operating at in the
context of own damage. Uh to your point
on the second one and to your first
point I did kind of give out the numbers
of the growth between new and old just
to reiterate quarter one new grew at
about 16% old book had grown at about
33%. Quarter two as I said the growth in
new has been largely flattish and the
growth in the renewal book has been
about 26%. On a half yearly basis the
growth in new has roughly been about 7
to 8% and the growth in the renewal book
has been close to about 30%. Uh 29 30%.
Uh so that's been the the break up. Now
in terms of where is that growth largely
coming in on the old side I think as I
said there is a significant thrust on us
in terms of making sure that we we are
able to retain as many customers of ours
uh and in so far as the initiative that
I kind of also spoke about but equally
what we have also been able to see is to
also get some expanded market as well
which is why if you see for example on
motor as a category where we used to
kind of possibly uh actually kind of see
us running at a market share of slightly
less than in fact 10%. Uh right now we
at a market share of close to about 11%.
Uh so in that sense um that's also kind
of aiding. So obviously we have also
been accreating uh some of the
businesses from uh market as well. So
it's been a combination of both but as I
said the endeavor is to try and see how
we can maximize retention uh
particularly at times when you see
possibly some kind of a slowdown from a
market perspective. Then we will
obviously as I said leverage our
strengths on uh distribution service and
technology to increase customer
retention.
Got it. Cool. Go just for a followup.
Can you give a trend last year on how
was our retentions and what is today in
motor just just to give a cover whether
it's driven by our own book. So on an
average I think what I would kind of say
uh sank is I think if you look at it
from a from a from a motor standpoint in
general and I'm largely just kind of
confining to private car and two wheeler
as categories. Uh on an average I would
say we would have seen an increase in
retentions ranging between 2 to 4%. Uh
that's the kind of increase in
retentions that one has seen and the
same trend line while you're talking in
the context of motors just to kind of
possibly expect a follow on on the
health side as well. uh I think even
there I think what we have seen is uh
obviously a slight uptick in so far as
uh our retention numbers are concerned
around pretty much around the similar
ranges. So I think as a as a company we
believe there's a lot that we can do in
so far as uh retaining the customers are
concerned and there and to that extent
is where we are driving a lot of our
initiatives around
thanks thanks for the answer. Thanks
Ankita.
Thank you. The next question is from the
line of Aditi Johi from JP Morgan.
Please go ahead.
[Applause]
Yeah. Uh thank you for taking my
question and good evening. Uh just
questions you can speak a little louder
that would be great. Thank you so much.
Yeah. Sorry. Uh is it better just two
questions uh from my side. Uh firstly on
the investment level side u I see that
the first half investment level was
slightly downward. Uh so can you please
help explain like the reason behind that
and going forward what do you think of
investment leverage trend and uh
secondly um on the uh uh retention side
the premium retention it's it was
slightly on the higher side um so I just
want to understand your strategy uh
going forward will you plan to retain
more on your books or uh how are you
thinking about it yeah that's all thank
you again I will go in the in the
reverse sequence uh So uh so if you look
at all the premium retention as I said
it's largely a function of the change in
the business mix uh as I kind of
outlined at the beginning I think in
quarter two relatively our sourcing on
the commercial lines have been uh
relatively muted uh where we kind of
typically have slightly higher than
extent higher higher reinsurance extent
and therefore to that extent retentions
are lower and given that we were
cautious that book has grown at a
relatively slower pace.
Compared to that I think we have seen a
significant uptake on both the retail
lines which is both retail health as
well as uh our motor lines of businesses
both of which predominantly we end up
retaining pretty much everything on the
net account. So hence to that extent is
where you will have you would have
possibly seen a slight uptick uh in so
far as the premium retentions are
concerned. to your point on what can we
expect going ahead. I think purely very
difficult to comment on a number because
it's all depends on how we see the
momentum play out in terms of business
different lines of businesses. But if
you ask us is there any change in the
thought process in terms of uh retention
versus reinsurance at this point of time
obviously there is no change in stance
but obviously we will take it as we play
through once the discussions for the
reinsurance programs happen at the
beginning of quarter 4 uh of maybe the
next calendar year beginning. So that is
where we are on premium retention to
your point on investment leverage. Um I
think uh which is again something that
we put out as a part of the opening
transcript in the in the context of the
market being a little slow particularly
in quarter 2. Uh if you'd have seen as I
said industry grew at about 13% we grew
at 20 in Q1 uh viz that market grew at
about 2% at thereabout in quarter 2 we
grew at roughly at about 10%. So to that
extent the fact that there has been a
relative slowdown in growth that
obviously kind of acts as a factor in so
far as u let's say the uh investment
leverage is concerned and secondly in
general if you would have seen the trend
line uh Q2 over Q1 uh generally the the
investment leverage seems to show a
declining trend and this trend starts to
reverse as we kind of head into the
festive season or maybe quarter three
where you will see start seeing a lot
more collections kind of play through
and hence I think to that extent is
where we are
on a I would say on a on a normal
trajectory I think broadly what we
should say is I think we have talked
about trying to maintain a investment
leverage of around four times I think
that's broadly the trend line that one
should expect but in a particular
quarter you can always see some of these
abrasions play and what also one more
thing just to add is mathematically
speaking if your growth of your if your
growth of profit is higher than the
growth of investment There can be a bit
of a denominator that will come out. Uh
it should get moderated with cash flows
over time.
Sure. Got it. Thank you so much. Thank
you.
Thank you. The next question comes from
the line of Nidh from Invest. Please go
ahead. Uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh
so my question is on motor TP. In motor
TP last three years uh there is no price
hike. uh and uh uh uh because of which
uh the loss ratio in the segment should
ideally be going up and some of the
companies I think also are going slow in
the motor TP. So what is giving us
confidence that the business that we are
underwriting
is of appropriate quality uh in terms of
profitability.
So the Nidesh uh yes there's been no
hike and I spoke about that just some
time back. Uh uh the configuration in
terms of how a book is placed uh the
contribution of commercial vehicle is
around 21 or you know and we always said
we remain in that range of 18 19 to 23
24% is what we expect the commercial
vehicle is which is the bare minimum. we
are more driven by private car and uh
two-heer. Uh so there is a mix and
selection that comes into play. Uh
clearly yes industry would love to see
in certain categories uh uh increase on
the uh third party premium and we
continue to be in discussion with the
regulator and all the other authorities
who are involved in that. uh but we stay
committed to our process of selection
and the rigor uh that which we go
through even in times when industry was
doing extremely well in certain
categories we had let go uh and had
shown a declining trend so we have stuck
to our course and we every reason to
believe that uh we should be able to
play play it out the way we have been
giving our numbers that's all I can say
at this point of time
the 60% combined loss ratio that we are
showing one motor TP uh is it a function
of uh uh uh decline in uh decline in
accident incidents or uh so this number
looks pretty good. So why that is how we
are able to deliver this number? Is it
our underwriting or it is just different
decline in uh decline in incidence of
the accidents or it is the benefit of
motor motor vehicle act that we are
getting now. So the last so again Nidesh
I I I think we have kind of reiterated
this even in our quarter one earnings
call uh particularly in the last piece
in terms of are we factoring in any
element of maybe a benefit in the
context of the likely implementation of
the six-month rule the short answer is
no. Uh so at this point of time we are
not necessarily factoring in anything in
the context of reserving uh at least so
far as the law of limitation is
concerned. uh but if you ask us um I
think so far as uh third party is
concerned as I keep saying uh you should
ideally start looking at this number
over longer cycles because of the
development of the inherent nature of
the business in terms of how the loss
development takes place and that's the
reason why we said uh generally at an
aggregate level the range that we are
comfortable operating at is between that
65 to 70% kind of a threshold and even
the point that Sanjiv made in terms of
our mix of business there If you would
have seen I think uh a large part of our
third party is significantly kind of
also contributed by the relatively
higher mix that we have on private car
and two wheelers relative to let's say
the exposures that one has in so far as
the commercial vehicle segment is
concerned. So hence uh that's also a
factor that plays out and in general I
think what we have also been able to do
not just now over periods uh I think we
have been able to significantly work on
making sure that we are able to identify
pockets which we believe are viable from
an underwriting standpoint uh and uh and
to that extent that aids in risk
selection and if you also remember even
within CV while I said we have been
underweight I think the call that we
took if you remember almost about four
five years back is to stay invested in
the segment where we think there is an
opportunity we would possibly take those
calls in possibly earmarking some
capital on doing the right risk
selection and in hindsight I think we
have actually seen some of these calls
play out to our advantage. So all in all
I think multiple factors that is aiding
but as I keep saying we just want to
reiterate I think the range that we are
comfortable operating is between a 65 to
70%.
Sure. And this last question on two
wheeler in two wheeler the sector growth
has been reasonably strong but our share
of two wheeler business on a y basis in
h1 has declined from 27 25%. So what is
happening there?
So that's primly the mixes I think again
as we keep saying uh it's all a function
of how you see the uh see the uh market
play out um and and obviously uh uh I
think as things as as let's say for
example Q3 typically the cycle could
again undergo a change uh once you see
some of the demands kind of picking up
so automatically you will see the mix of
business within motor undergoing a
change. uh so all in all for us there is
no specific uh there's no specific
change in thought processes unless you
no I'll just add this so the decline of
28 to 25 which you are referring to
Nidesh is more the configuration uh we
haven't lost market share two wheeler
but we we have gained more in private
car at a faster cliff so that changes
the percentage distribution uh of
business otherwise motor overall if you
look at it and which is a bigger number
to see we've moved from a 9.8 date kind
of a market share to almost 11 which is
10.9%. So there's an overall gain and in
that journey as the whichever way the
configuration comes out it's more driven
by output of uh percentages of portfolio
distribution not that we have lost
anything in two villa. Sure.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. The next question is from the
line of Jay K from Jeff. Please go
ahead. Uh thank you for the opportunity.
Uh just a bit on the renewal book. Uh
can you help us understand how the
renewal rates across the the segments
within motor have been trending uh and
and how how much has improved over the
last say one or two years uh and and
maybe even the last two quarters is is
that contributing uh to the renewal
growth.
So giants I think I already kind of
possibly answered that. uh I don't think
we're talking specifically in the
context of uh specific subsegments
within motor. I think all that we can
talk about is to say that at an
aggregate level motor as a category we
have seen an improvement in retention
broadly kind of increasing between two 2
to 4%. And that's what I kind of also
referred to helping us relatively grow
our grow our proportion of the old
business the breakup of which I had
given in response to one of the
questions. And do you expect this to
continue improving from here? I mean
basis the efforts that you guys are
taking uh on on improving the the
renewals. The short answer is yes Jen
because I think one of the other points
that I spoke about is our increased
thrust that we are putting on customer
service. And if you see one of the other
things that we keep talking a lot about
which is also there in our annual report
and even in multiple of our uh of our
disclosures that we have made is clearly
at least in so far as customer
satisfaction score slash NPS scores are
concerned it is only seeing an uptick
and that automatically kind of in some
sense aids customers to kind of stay
hooked uh at least in so far as
retentions are concerned. Hence to that
extent that's definitely a factor and
the fact that we are also able to divert
maybe a lot of our customers in so far
as the preferred provider network is
concerned where again so far as the
customer is concerned they are assured
of uh clearly two things one obviously
it helps in so far as managing the
overall average cost of claims but two
and more importantly what we're able to
kind of assure the customer there is the
quality of repair and let's say the
relative turnaround time that we are
able to exhibit um in so far as uh
servicing those uh claims are concerned.
So that is exactly what a customer looks
for when he or she gets a claim. I think
the earliest possible time within which
a vehicle can be repaired and given back
that possibly kind of results into a a
delightful experience and there we have
seen a significant uptick on the PPN
network which again is kind of
translating into an improved retention
for us.
Thank you. Just sort of one last follow
up on this. Uh in terms of channels, uh
is some channel sort of helping over
others in terms of improving the
retention rates over here?
Channel wise there is uh I think again
Jen uh
channel wise uh see when it comes to
retaining our own customers we have our
own direct reach out to them. uh to some
extent uh it's channel agnostic uh but
yes certain categories may end up having
better retention than uh other channel
website has a good retention agency
business has a much better retention uh
OEM relatively at time get distributed
may have a lower one but when we
approach our customers through call
center in terms of retaining it uh uh
it's more a process improvement and a
consistent reach out that we have
created which is helping us retain
is digital slightly better over over
agency over here. Historically, it's
been better. There's no there's no doubt
on that. Yes.
Thank you very much and congratulations
on a great set of numbers. Thank you.
Thanks, J. Thank you so much. Thank you.
We have the next question from the line
of Pritish Opal from Securities. Please
go ahead.
Yeah. Hi, thanks so for taking my
question. Um, just wanted to understand
the context of the rising cat losses.
you know some color in terms of how the
pricing is on the reinsurance side
specifically on the you know the CAT
events how do you see that I mean
possibly moving the next year or uh in
the medium term uh and um in case there
is uh some kind of reinsurance price
hike what strategy do you think would be
viable in terms of you know at an
industry level the pass passing on of
the cost or the absorption and uh
Second, I wanted to understand in the
health segment uh you know what is the
mix between the old and the new book and
if possibly you could give some color on
the loss ratio split between the renewal
book and the new book.
Uh so I think on the on the first one um
in so far as writing rising cat losses
are concerned I think your point is
absolutely right and that is exactly
what we kind of uh keep looking for. Now
again if you were to slightly go back to
history uh if you remember almost about
four five years back when the market had
seen stress particularly in fire line of
business at that point of time clearly
reinsurers had stepped in and they had
said in case if companies wants to avail
appropriate reinsurance capacity the
market has to be more disciplined in so
far as pricing is concerned and to that
extent is where they had kind of
calibrated pricing terms and the extent
of possibly reinsurance commissions that
they would be kind of ascribing to
individual companies and in that context
if you'd have seen from an IC alumba
standpoint given that we were largely
exhibiting a profitable book in terms of
our ability to reselect better quality
book we were actually able to keep
improving our panel of reinsurers and
relatively our terms on reinsurance were
also better. uh now uh and therefore now
when you look at in that context if the
market further improve pricing that is
very very positive uh because that in
some sense aids market to get far more
disciplined because if reinsurers were
to kind of define an increase in price
then that's a call that companies will
have to take in terms of their ability
to pass on to let's say what they're
able to do in so far as keeping it on
the net. So any increase in pricing but
all this will start getting reflected
once we do our reinsurance uh
conversations which will happen towards
quarter 4 of this year. So we will see
how that plays out. uh to your point on
uh on the health side I think uh for us
the growth I think is aided by uh both
contribution by as as I said even on the
motor where I spoke about on retention
even at that point of time I had said
even on health there is a significant
focus for us and therefore to that
extent we have also seen an improvement
in the retention ratios of customers on
health as well and in so far as the uh
growth numbers I think it is a growth
that is aided by both retention of
customers And more importantly also if
you see I think the newly launched
solution elevate particularly that we
launched in quarter two of this year
that has been received very well across
multiple stakeholders and that's why
when you look at retail health as a
category the market share which was
largely hovering around 2.9% or
thereabout for quarter 2 that number
stands at about 3.5%. while it's an
outcome of just one quarter as we
launched this solution but obviously I
think we are quite excited and happy
with the way how this has played out and
honestly we will have to kind of keep
this momentum going as we kind of look
forward um to your point on what could
be the split in so far as the loss ratio
of new and the renewal book is concerned
honestly to my mind I think that's
purely a function of what kind of a mix
of business that we write um and our our
objective will be to obviously write a
combination of both new and renewal and
that's why I kind of talked about in the
context of the overall loss ratio that
we are comfortable on the retail health
side which is roughly at around 70%. The
mix there on is the split between new
and renewable will be purely a function
of what mix of business that we write.
Okay. Uh so just one followup uh you
know in terms of uh uh the uh industry
loss ratios that we seeing uh across the
board uh have been rising. So is that
driven more by frequency of claims or is
it also from I mean or is it just purely
claim size that has been increased? Uh
such frequency numbers at the industry
levels are not available. So very
difficult to comment but if the loss
ratio is the one which is contributing
more. It can be a contribution of
nothing but frequency and the average
claim size that comes into play is uh
what our understanding is. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Thank you. Okay. Thank you.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen. We will
take that as our last question for
today. I would now like to hand the
conference over to Mr. Sanjiv Mantri for
closing comments. Over to you sir. Yeah.
Thank you so much for joining in. I
think we're in the midst of uh the
festive season. Uh wishing wishing you
all a great happy Diwali to you and your
family members. Stay good, stay fit,
stay happy and uh uh we are excited in
terms of what quarter 3 entails for us.
Uh and I hope it wish it brings us all
good luck. Thank you so much and look
forward to interacting with you uh one
to one as and when your time permits.
Thank you. Thank you so much. Thanks.
Thank you.
Thank you on behalf of ICICI Lumbard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us. You may now disconnect
your lines.